Run to live... kill to survive.
Essential Killing is a thriller, war film directed by Jerzy Skolimowski.
A Taliban soldier struggles to survive after he escapes his
captors and flees into the Polish countryside.
Mohammed, played by Vincent Gallo.
Margaret, played by Emmanuelle Seigner.
Interrogation Officer, played by David L. Price.
American Contractor 1, played by Zach Cohen.
American Contractor 2, played by Iftach Ophir.
Helicopter Pilot 1, played by Nicolai Cleve Broch.
Essential Killing is a 2010 survival political thriller film co-written and directed by
Jerzy Skolimowski and starring Vincent Gallo and Emmanuelle Seigner.
Gallo stars as an Islamic insurgent who finds himself fighting for
survival in a frozen woodland, pursued by soldiers.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics,
with many praising Gallo's performance.
The film won several accolades, including the Special Jury Prize at the 67th Venice
International Film Festival, while Gallo also won the Volpi Cup for Best Actor.
The tone is intense.